Stephan Santos

SEATTLE, WA

CONTACT

https://www.stephansantos.com stephan.pssantos@gmail.com (206) 307-4338

SUMMARY: Software engineer with ~4 years of professional development work. Successfully delivered multiple individual and team projects, participating in every stage of the software development lifecycle from conception through to long-term end user support.

SKILL SET

LANGUAGES

C#, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS

TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

Node.js, .NET, PowerShell, Git, Docker, React, Blazor, OpenAPI, Postman, Adobe Creative Suite **SERVICES**

Azure DevOps, Azure Cloud Services, Dynamics CRM, MS Power Platform, SharePoint

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KING COUNTY PROSECUTING ATTORNEY'S OFFICE IT DEPARTMENT (SEATTLE, WA)

Senior Applications Developer

Jul 2021 – Apr 2022

- Prepared data analytics dashboards and reports through Power BI and SSRS, expanding the number of available reports by over 75% and helping to facilitate data-driven decision-making within the company.
- Facilitated the purchase and roll-out of commercial off-the-shelf software or SaaS products as the technical point of contact for vendors, coordinating integration and deployment, organizing training and communications, and preparing internal troubleshooting and end user documentation.

Journey Applications Developer

Oct 2019 – Jul 2021

With an agile team, delivered multiple Dynamics 365 applications as part of a suite of business applications used by a third of staff members that allowed the company to drop certain legacy applications, achieve a 90% reduction in local network storage costs, and ease work from home transitions. Elicited and analyzed requirements, helped design data schemas, configured forms and logic, developed plugins, configured MS Power Platform and Azure interactions, scripted deployment pipelines, prepared documentation.

Web Developer

Jul 2018 – Oct 2019

- Delivered a React web application hosted on Azure used regularly by over 2,000 local government employees to register new legal documents, reducing administrative time from days to minutes. Integrates with existing login gateways and programmatically connected to company's SharePoint storage.
- Provided new features, content, and support for SiteCore CMS, SharePoint, Teams, and the company's legacy MS office applications (Excel and Word VB scripts, Access databases.)
- Coordinated planning, communication, training, and document preparation for transition from local network storage to OneDrive for individual user file storage.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE DEVELOPER ASSOCIATE - Achieved February 2022 COMPTIA A+ - Achieved July 2019

ATENEO DE MANILA UNIVERSITY (QUEZON CITY, PHILIPPINES) - 2010-2014

- Graduated with a bachelor's degree in information design.
- Key Coursework: Web Development, Visual Communication, User Experience, Wireframing